I'll do the investigation.
由我來查吧
Huh?
什麼？
Why did she tell you my father had been murdered?
為什麼會說我的父親是被殺害的？
If he framed your father in some way,
如果那個人真的陷害了你的父親
I'll never forgive him.
那我絕對饒不了他
I found it.
找到了
My father left a recording.
我父親有留下紀錄
I wanted you to listen with me.
希望你能跟我一起聽
This is a record of the environmental energy corruption case.
這是環境能源貪汙案紀錄
This case is clearly fabricated.
這起案件明顯是被捏造出來的
The e-mail that the prosecution submitted as evidence
被檢方當作證據提出的郵件
is completely fake.
完全是假造的
Why is this witness changing his story?
這種單方面的翻案是怎麼回事？
Was it entirely a setup?
全都是設計好的嗎？
So it was my dad after all.
果然是我爸害的
You and I should stop meeting each other.
我們兩個就別再見面了
Masaki?
真樹？
What's the matter?
你怎麼了？
Hang on.
你忍一下
Takashi.
貴志
What's going on between you two?
我在問你這究竟是什麼情況
I won't meet him anymore.
也不會再見面了
I don't want to meet him.
我也不想再見他
He has cancer.
他得了癌症
He's actually critically ill.
而且病情相當嚴重
We need to talk.
我有話要跟你說
Come in.
進來
Hey you.
這位先生
I…
放火的人…
set the fire.
就是我
So you're saying you did it.
所以你承認
Is this correct?
是你做的，是吧？
Yes.
沒錯
I did it.
是我幹的
Just after ten last night, here in Mizuho Ward, Yokohama,
昨日晚間十點後 位在橫濱市瑞穗區的
there was a fire at the residence of attorney, Koichiro Nogi.
野木浩一郎律師住家發生火災
His unemployed son, Masaki, who was near the site
其失業的長子真樹 人在現場並涉有嫌疑
admitted to setting fire to the house and was arrested at the scene.
該名嫌犯聲稱自己在住家縱火 當場被警方視為現行犯逮捕…
I listened to the voice recorder.
我聽過錄音機的內容了
Yeah.
這樣啊
I wonder if he did it for you.
他是不是為了你才放火的？
For your father.
可能也是為了你父親
Regarding the fire that occurred in Mizuho-ku, Yokohama last night.
為您播報昨夜於橫濱市瑞穗區 發生的火災事件
According to the police, at the time of the fire,
據警方所說，當時野木先生家中
only Mr. Nogi and his son were present in the house.
僅有他與涉有嫌疑的兒子 真樹先生在場
The police are investigating the motive--
嫌犯的真樹先生在自家縱火的原因…
Arson? What's happening?
縱火？這是怎麼回事？
If that's Kanagawa Prefecture, then it's Yokohama District.
既然是神奈川縣警出馬
Why?
為什麼？
Even if she finds out something,
就算她知道什麼內情
she has a duty to be confidential.
也有保密的義務
She can't tell us anything.
她想說也不能說
What if his father dies as a consequence?
如果他父親就這麼過世了
Would it be arson-homicide?
那不就成了縱火殺人嗎？
It would be arson
到時候他會被控縱火罪
and a murder charge.
還有殺人罪
Both.
這兩項罪名
Good morning.
早安
You're up already?
你已經起床啦？
Whoa, I didn't realize how late it was.
天啊，都這麼晚了，我都沒發現
Go wash your face.
趕緊去洗臉
Get ready to go. Hurry!
去做準備，動作快！
Yeah… I'll hurry…
好，我快一點…
Huh? Where's your dad?
奇怪，你爸呢？
Stop there.
停下來
Excuse me.
我想問一件事
What?
想問什麼？
What will happen to me after this?
之後我會怎麼樣？
You'll be referred to the district public prosecutors office shortly
你不久後就會被移交地檢
to decide if you'll be detained.
檢方會決定是否拘留你
If you're detained, it'll take ten days to decide if you're indicted or not.
被拘留後，他們會在10天後 決定是否起訴你
Or 20 days maximum.
最多20天左右
The interrogation will be long.
審訊會持續一段時間
Try to organize it in your head now.
好好釐清自己的思緒
-Come in. -Pardon me, ma'am.
-進來 -打擾了
I want you to take this case.
你來接手這個案子
Me?
我嗎？
It's my order as the branch chief.
這是分部長的命令
CASE OF NOGI RESIDENCE ARSON
（野木家縱火事件）
ARSON OF INHABITED BUILDINGS
（對現居建築物等縱火）
MASAKI NOGI BORN JUNE 12, 1989
（野木真樹 出生於1989年6月12日）
I'm Nishimura, the prosecutor.
我是檢察官，西村
You have the right to remain silent if you don't wish to speak.
您有權保持緘默 不用違背自己的意願陳述
You were arrested for the crime of arson of inhabited buildings.
您這次有放火燒燬 現供人使用之住宅的嫌疑，因此被捕
Please confirm. First, your name…
現在我要跟您核對名字
Mr. Masaki Nogi, aged 35.
野木真樹先生，現年35歲
Place of birth, Yokohama.
您的出生地為神奈川縣橫濱市瑞穗區
Currently unemployed.
目前沒有工作
Do you affirm these facts I've read as being true?
以上陳述的事實 確定是您本人所做的嗎？
Is this all correct?
確定沒錯嗎？
I wanted to know the truth.
我想知道真相
That was the sole reason I wanted to become a prosecutor.
為了達成這個目的 我立志成為檢察官
To achieve results as the prosecutor in charge,
身為主任檢察官，為了要做出成果
you wanted to indict Diet member Azuma at any cost!
無論如何都想起訴東議員！
Kanade.
小奏
I love you.
我喜歡你
So it was my dad after all.
果然是我爸害的
You and I should stop meeting each other.
我們兩個就別再見面了
That's why I am now…
所以我現在…
I'm Nishimura, the prosecutor.
我是檢察官，西村
Nice to meet you.
請多指教
THE FIRST INTERROGATION
（第一次訊問）
Today you have been referred
你這次有…
on the crime of arson of inhabited buildings.
放火燒燬現供人使用之住宅的嫌疑 因此被移送至此
Do you affirm that you set the fire?
是你放的火，確定沒錯嗎？
I did it.
是我做的
I'd like to verify your actions on the day of the arson.
我現在要來確認你犯案當天的行動
Yes.
好的
The night before,
案發前一晚
you were admitted to Minato General Hospital in Yokohama
你因為腹痛
as an emergency with stomach pain.
緊急住進橫濱市立港綜合醫院
You left the hospital after 9:00 the next day.
在隔天早上9點後出院
Yes.
是的
Then you walked around Yokohama,
出院後在橫濱街頭步行
and at 5:40 p.m.
下午5點40分
you called your father, Mr. Koichiro Nogi, on your cell phone.
用手機打給父親的野木浩一郎先生
-Come in. -Then you went to his house.
-進來 -接著你去了老家
I did.
沒錯
That day, your mother…
那天令堂…
She is not your birth mother, is she?
她不是你的生母，對吧？
She's my father's second wife.
她是我爸的再婚對象
So on that day, your stepmother and your sister
當天你繼母和妹妹
were in Tokyo to see a theater performance.
去東京觀賞舞台劇，因此不在家
It was only you and Mr. Koichiro Nogi present at the house.
住家中只有你和浩一郎先生在
Yes.
對
Mr. Nogi invited you into the living room.
浩一郎先生讓你進客廳
The two of you talked.
你們倆在此交談
Later, it became an argument
後來起了口角
and you lost your temper.
你一時火大
There was a lighter on a shelf nearby.
便拿起在附近櫃子的燃燒式打火機
You grabbed it and lit it.
然後點了火
When you threw it towards Mr. Nogi,
將其扔向浩一郎先生
the curtains caught on fire from the flame.
導致窗簾起火燃燒
Yes.
對
Then you left the house with your father still in the room.
你什麼都沒做 扔下父親不管，跑出家門
Is this all correct?
沒錯嗎？
Yes, that is correct.
你說的都對
I want to ask you something.
我想問你一個問題
What is it?
問什麼？
If you lit the flame because you lost your temper,
如果你是受怒氣驅使而縱火
then does it mean you didn't visit the house with the intent of arson?
代表你去父親家的目的 並不是為了縱火，對吧？
I didn't.
的確不是
Then,
既然如此
please tell me what you were talking about
能否請你說明當下的狀況？
and what caused the argument.
像是你跟令尊聊了些什麼
What was the conversation about at the time?
以及引爆口角的導火線
Can I invoke my right to silence?
我可以行使緘默權嗎？
Right now, your father
令尊被送進醫院
is on the edge between life and death in the hospital where he was taken.
如今徘徊在生死邊緣
He's suffering from inhalation burns
火災導致他氣管灼傷
and carbon monoxide poisoning from the fire
以及一氧化碳中毒
which resulted in cerebral hypoxia.
引發了腦缺氧的症狀
All because
這些全是你縱火造成的
How do you feel about this fact?
你對此有什麼想法？
How… do I feel?
就算你問我，我也答不出來
Do you have any feelings of remorse?
你心中有悔意嗎？
Not particularly.
並沒有
Next, I'd like to ask you about your actions since then.
那我繼續問 我想問你離開住家後的行動
According to the police…
警方現場勘查後…
On this day,
結果這一天下來
Masaki didn't say much of anything in the end.
真樹幾乎什麼也沒說
What about the time between when you left the house
你離開住家後
and when the police officer asked you questions?
到警察向你攀談前 應該間隔了一小段時間吧？
Thanks for your work.
辛苦了
We need the pre-indictment detention request.
麻煩你辦理拘留申請
Yes.
好的
Are you going somewhere?
你接下來要幹嘛？
To the crime scene.
我去趟案發現場
The crime scene?
案發現場？
Something is bothering me.
有件事想弄清楚
I see.
知道了
By the way…
那個…
Huh? Isn't it still during working hours?
怎麼了？現在去辦 不會超過下班時間吧？
Not that. It's about Masaki Nogi, the suspect.
我不是想說那件事 涉嫌縱火的野木真樹
Isn't he the one who had that big fight in the lobby of Yokohama District Court?
不就是在橫濱地方法院的大廳 和野木律師大吵一架的那個人嗎？
What?
什麼？
You know, after that illegal drug possession case.
你想想，就是在 持有違禁藥品的那樁案子後
What the hell is this?
這算什麼啊？
You killed Eisuke Tsuji, didn't you?
是你殺害了辻英介吧？
Kanade, wait!
小奏，等一下！
Let's go, Kaji.
加地，我們走吧
Are you sure?
這樣好嗎？
Yes, he is.
沒錯
Well, I was wondering if he had a long-standing feud with his father.
也沒什麼啦，只是覺得 他和父親間是不是從當時就有起爭執
Maybe involving asking for money?
像是來找父親要錢之類的？
Could be.
可能吧
I'll keep that in mind too.
我也會一併納入考量
-Thank you. -Yes.
-謝謝你 -不客氣
-Goodbye.
-辛苦了 -你也辛苦了
I wonder if Kaji noticed
加地他是不是察覺到 真樹和我認識彼此？
Even if he knows,
即使他發現了也無妨
I'll find out in my own way
我會用自己的方式找出答案
the truth about this case.
好好面對這件案子
This is Kaji.
我是加地
Do you have time to talk now?
現在方便講電話嗎？
What was Masaki's…
真樹…
What was suspect Masaki Nogi's motive?
嫌犯的野木真樹
Why did he commit arson?
為何選擇犯案？
What was the reason he decided to set the fire?
他為何會生出縱火的想法？
On the morning of the fire,
火災發生的當天早上
Masaki left the hospital,
真樹在出院之後
and walked in the city.
在街頭遊走
The reason for him visiting his father must have been the voice recorder.
他會找上父親，除了錄音機那件事
It must be.
肯定沒有別的原因
This is the truth I discovered.
這就是我所追查到的真相
So it was my dad after all.
果然是我爸害的
What if he went to the house
如果他去父親家的本意
with the intention of arson-homicide from the start?
就是為了去縱火殺人呢？
-Good afternoon.
-辛苦了
Nevertheless,
就算是這樣
would he try to kill so suddenly?
人一動殺心，會突然出手殺人嗎？
There seems to be a big gap between his motive and actions.
他的動機和行為幾乎無法劃上等號吧
Thenjust as Masaki said
還是說真樹所言為真
the two had an argument that night, and…
父子在當天夜裡吵了起來…
I've had enough!
你給我差不多一點！
Masaki lost his temper.
真樹無法壓抑怒火
He lit a lighter he found lying around.
點燃在現場的打火機
The curtains caught fire from the flame.
令窗簾起火燃燒
A lighter…
打火機啊
Ms. Nishimura.
西村檢座
-Oh, good afternoon. -Good afternoon.
-哦，辛苦你了 -辛苦了
Did the fire start in the living room as the suspect stated?
起火點真如嫌犯本人供稱的那樣 在客廳嗎？
We're still trying to determine.
目前還在確認
Was the lighter found?
打火機呢？
Not yet.
還沒找到
I see.
我明白了
Considering the house burned down completely,
從房子徹底被燒毀這一前提來看
something is bothering me.
有一點讓我有些在意
Why did he use a lighter?
他為何要用打火機縱火？
What triggered him?
是什麼契機逼得他放火？
Are you Ms. Nishimura, the prosecutor?
你是西村檢座嗎？
Yes. Thank you for taking the time to see me.
沒錯，抱歉在你忙碌時叨擾
Is he still in critical condition?
他果然還是沒脫離險境啊？
Yes.
是的
He seems to have inhaled a large amount of carbon monoxide.
估計他應該吸入了大量的一氧化碳
A large amount?
大量？
The respiratory tract burn is also severe.
再加上氣管灼燒嚴重
There's a possibility he won't wake up.
有可能再也醒不過來
Is that so?
這樣啊
Of course, we'll try our best, but…
雖然我們院方會盡力救治他…
What really happened between Masaki and his father
案發當天，真樹和野木律師之間
on the day of the fire?
實際上發生了什麼事情？
Kanade's the prosecutor in the case against Masaki?
小奏成了主辦真樹案件的檢察官？
Yeah. That's what I heard.
對，似乎就是那樣沒錯
No way.
不會吧
Is it going to be okay?
那樣不會出問題嗎？
Well, it does sound like a tough job.
這個嘛，我覺得應該不太好辦
Her superiors don't know about her relationship with Masaki?
上級不知道小奏和真樹的關係嗎？
I imagine they wouldn't let her do the job if they knew.
如果知情就不會讓她接下此案了
Tomo.
小知
I…
我…
What?
怎麼了？
I quit the law firm.
我離開現在這間律師事務所了
Huh?
什麼？
-Why? -Actually…
-為什麼？ -其實啊
to be precise,
準確來說
it's like I didn't have a choice but to quit.
我只有辭職這條路可走
Did you do something bad?
你幹壞事了？
It's not that.
你誤會了
I didn't…
壞事…
do anything.
我可沒幹
My goodness! Don't scare me like that!
討厭啦！不要這樣說話！
It's just that the law firm was poorly managed.
那間律師事務所經營不善
They started getting strict about quotas.
績效指標變得越來越嚴苛
I'm looking for a job at other law firms.
我還找了其他事務所
But I'm having trouble finding one.
但不太順利
So I…
所以我…
kind of asked--
想問一下…
Check. I don't mind.
沒關係，你看吧
Okay.
好
No way.
不會吧
International Cultural Law Firm.
國際文化法律事務所
They want to interview me.
要找我去面試耶
International Cultural Law Firm?
國際文化法律事務所？
That's awesome! That's great!
你真厲害！太好了！
I didn't like my family to start with.
我原本就厭惡我的家庭
I mean,
更確切地說
I didn't like him.
我討厭那個人
By "him" you mean your father, right?
你指的是令尊，沒錯吧？
But why so much hatred?
為何如此厭惡他？
I wonder why myself.
這是為什麼呢？
Shoplifting…
我以前…
Long ago I shoplifted once.
曾偷過東西
It was from a convenience store, when I was in junior high.
我還是國中生時，和一群當地的朋友
I was goofing around with childhood friends.
去了超商，一時興起就偷了商品
What did you steal?
你偷了什麼？
Vanilla ice cream.
香草冰淇淋
Trading cards.
就是卡牌遊戲啦
I wasn't caught that time,
當下沒被人發現
but my friend shoplifted again right after that.
偷完不久後，那個朋友又行竊了
And I was suspected.
連我也背上嫌疑
My dad said to me at the time,
當時我爸告訴我
"Whatever they ask you,
“不管對方問什麼
don't ever admit you did it."
死也不能說自己‘偷了’
"Just insist you didn't."
要堅稱自己‘沒偷’
"If you keep denying it,
打死不鬆口
that'd be the truth."
就會變成真相”
I realized something at that moment.
我當時就心想
I thought, "Oh."
“哦
"I get it."
這樣啊
"So this is
原來這就是他的作風”
Did you follow his instructions?
所以你是聽從了那項指示？
What do you think?
你怎麼想？
If you did what he told you,
如果你聽了
I guess you wouldn't have this hatred toward your father.
也許就不會像現在這樣 討厭自己的父親
The Nogi family is prominent in Yokohama, isn't it?
野木一家在橫濱算是名門吧？
Your grandfather was the founder of Nikkai Shipbuilding Company.
你爺爺是日海造船的創始人
Your father is an attorney.
父親是律師
I think ordinary people would envy your background.
在常人看來 這種家庭環境應該非常令人羨慕
I don't fit in with them because look at me.
但我這樣的性子和那種家庭合不來
After you dropped out of university, where did you go?
大學退學後，你去了哪裡？
If you're feeling ill, please tell us.
身體不適時，請你說出來
In that case--
要是不舒服…
I went to the Tohoku region.
我去了東北地區
I had an acquaintance there.
碰巧有我的熟人在那邊
An acquaintance?
熟人？
A tutor
是我念高中
from high school and before college.
還有落榜重讀時的家教
They were doing volunteer work in Miyako after the great earthquake.
地震發生後，那個人在宮古做志工
Miyako?
宮古？
Miyako in Iwate Prefecture.
岩手縣的宮古市
I was there helping to clear the dirt and so forth.
我在當地進行砂石清理等工作
And you didn't tell anyone at all about this?
此事你沒告知任何人？
I didn't.
沒有
Why?
為什麼？
I wanted to change my ways.
因為我想換一種活法
I felt…
我覺得自己…
like I was totally naive.
太嬌慣了
About your university days?
是指學生時期的你嗎？
Although I got in,
我上了大學
I wasn't attending classes but just hanging around.
但卻不去上課，只是遊手好閒
I didn't have any purpose at all.
沒有任何目標
So you didn't enjoy it there?
上大學不快樂嗎？
I did.
很快樂
It was the best time…
那是我至今為止的人生中…
of my life.
最開心的時光
Thinking back now…
如今回想起來
that period…
那段時間
was the happiest time.
最讓我感到幸福
Doing silly things all the time…
雖然盡做些傻事…
but I was happy.
但還是很幸福
I fell in love there.
也喜歡上了一個人
Show me.
借我看
W-What?
做什麼？
Your answers, so, I, can, cheat.
借我抄答案
Law major?
你是法律系的？
-Yes. -Me too.
-對 -我也是
Don't you know me?
你不認識我嗎？
Did you have a partner?
你交過女朋友？
Perhaps someone more
是比女朋友
than that.
更重要的存在
I love you.
我喜歡你
Do you know there's a way to hold hands that can never be separated?
你知道絕對不會鬆手的握法嗎？
When someone who you thought loved you suddenly disappears,
深愛自己的人忽然消失
it hurts. I know.
真的很難受
Until then, I didn't have
過往的人生裡
a lot of people I could open my heart up to.
我一直沒遇上可以敞開心扉的對象
But when I was with her,
然而和她在一起
I could be myself naturally.
我能自然地展現真實的自己
A minute longer together…
哪怕只多一分鐘
A second longer together…
哪怕只多一秒
That's what I was wishing for.
我也想和她在一起
I don't really know what that was.
我也搞不太懂那是怎麼回事
I think there was a powerful mutual attraction.
會強烈地互相吸引，令人難以抵抗
Have you experienced
你曾有過
anything like that?
那樣的經驗嗎？
I have.
我也懂那種感受
Masaki, wait! Don't go! Masaki!
真樹，等一下！你不要走，真樹！
I'm sorry!
對不起！
Why did you break up with that person?
你為什麼會和對方分手？
Maybe because…
我覺得她和我在一起…
I thought it'd be too painful…
會承受超乎想像的痛苦
to stay together.
這就是原因
I didn't want to see her being sad.
我不想看到她傷心難過
Didn't you tell that person your honest feelings?
你沒把這些話告訴她？
No.
沒有
Don't you think that person
如果你坦誠相告
would have understood if you had?
或許她會體諒你
It's too complicated.
當時的情況太複雜了
I was probably…
就連我自己…
completely confused about it myself.
也思緒紊亂
So…
只覺得…
I thought I had to disappear.
唯有自己消失才能解決
Didn't you consider
你連一個理由都沒有給對方
those you abandoned without explanation?
最後還拋下她，你不曾為她想過嗎？
I wasn't considerate enough.
是我考慮不周
I guess I'm selfish.
我這個人就是自私
Would you say you have impulsive traits?
你天生就有這股衝動？
To want to throw everything away,
讓你想拋棄一切
wishing everything would be gone?
希望一切通通消失
Do you mean the fire?
你是指火災？
No, not just that.
不，也不全是火災
Hey, why are you asking me so many unrelated questions?
我問你，你怎麼老是問些 和案件無關的問題？
These are not unrelated questions.
並非毫無關聯
Your motive for committing the crime,
釐清你為何犯罪
your strained relationship with your father,
你和令尊之間有什麼齟齬
whether you regret what you've done or not…
你有沒有悔意
Our job is to find answers to these questions.
就是我們檢方的職責
Whether to indict or not
起訴或不起訴
depends on the decision of the prosecutor.
全取決於檢察官的判斷
Your life depends on it.
這可是關係到你的人生
We can't make the wrong decision.
我不能做出錯誤的決定
That's an intense job.
你的工作真偉大
I respect you.
讓我由衷尊敬
That's right.
對了
I thought at the time
我當時是覺得
if I could restart with a clean slate, I might feel so much better.
現在做個了結，重新開始 可能會讓心情舒暢些
If I burnt it all down
燒毀所有一切就行
and everything was gone…
全都消失算了
Excuse me.
那個…
What is it?
怎麼了？
Can I ask you one thing?
可以問個問題嗎？
Go on.
請說
How is he doing now?
你知道他的病況如何嗎？
I heard he was still unconscious.
聽說他仍然處於昏迷狀態
Is he…
他會就此…
going to die?
死去嗎？
Nobody knows that.
目前沒人知道
Including me.
包括我在內
That'll be it for today.
今天的訊問就此結束
Stand up.
起立
Prosecutor.
檢座
Yes.
是
These handcuffs…
手銬…
They're so cold.
真是冰冷啊
I just found out.
我之前都不曉得
You're going out now.
出去吧
YOKOHAMA DISTRICT PUBLIC PROSECUTORS OFFICE CHUO BRANCH
（橫濱地方檢察廳中央分部）
Yes.
請進
Ms. Nishimura.
西村檢座
I need to talk to you about what you said the other day.
我想就先前那件案子跟你聊聊
Yes.
沒問題
New evidence?
新證據？
Since what you mentioned stuck in my mind,
你說的話讓我耿耿於懷
I searched the garage in front of the house.
所以我查看了一樓的車庫
Yes.
這樣啊
CRIME SCENE NOGI RESIDENCE FLOOR PLAN LIVING ROOM
（犯罪現場野木宅格局圖 客廳）
Look at these.
請看這個
We found a piece of a burned-up plastic fuel can.
我找到了塑膠桶燒毀後的殘留物
We also detected gasoline on it.
並且從上頭驗出了汽油成分
Gasoline…
汽油…
Additionally,
不僅如此
there is a new report from a witness in the neighborhood.
附近還出現了新的目擊情報
-I'm home. -Hi.
-我回來了 -回來啦
-Interrogation again today? -Yeah.
-今天也是忙著訊問？ -對
What's this?
這是什麼？
It was in our delivery locker.
放在快遞櫃裡
Tomo brought it for us apparently.
好像是小知拿來的
-Tomo did? -Yeah.
-小知嗎？ -對
I know you're busy so I'll just leave this here.
我知道你很忙，就直接放著囉
They're in an insulated bag. Do a sniff test just in case.
料理在保冷袋裡 但還是要確認一下有沒有異味喔
You don't need to e-mail me. Hang in there. Tomo.
不用傳訊息給我，加油喔，小知留
We should eat.
就接受她的好意吧
Okay.
好
-I'll go change. -Okay.
-我去換個衣服 -好
This is comforting.
感覺好暖心
Yeah. I'm so grateful.
對啊，真是感謝她
Do they feed people in detention?
拘留室會按時供餐嗎？
What? Of course, they do.
什麼？當然會啊
Well…
我想問…
How long is he… Masaki going to be in there?
他…野木先生會被拘留多久？
Well, the maximum is 20 days.
這個嘛，最久20天
Whether he committed the crime or not,
先不提他是不是真的犯了罪
essentially,
我原本就覺得
I think he should get treatment.
他應該接受治療
Has it progressed?
他的病情惡化到那種地步了？
From the way he was in pain…
從他前陣子的疼痛症狀來看…
Takashi.
貴志
Where does it hurt?
你是哪裡痛？
From my right side…
從腹部的右側…
to my back.
一直到背部
I see…
這樣啊
Can you tell me again the situation of how you started the fire?
能不能再次詳細說明 你縱火當時的情況？
THE THIRD INTERROGATION
（第三次訊問）
As I've said many times, we got into an argument.
就跟前幾次的說法一樣
I found a lighter on the shelf.
我們倆起了口角
I threw the lighter, then the curtains caught on fire--
隨後我扔出櫃子上的打火機 窗簾燒了起來…
Mr. Koichiro Nogi quit smoking five years ago.
野木浩一郎先生早在五年前就戒菸了
Other family members don't recall it being there.
家人也不知道打火機是從何而來
Then who's lighter was it?
若真是如此，你認為那個打火機
Why was it there?
究竟會是誰的？
I don't know.
天曉得
But there was a lighter there.
但現場確實有打火機
The lighter was on the shelf next to the sofa.
打火機放在沙發旁邊的櫃子上
When you got into an argument,
你們父子在爭執完後
you lit the lighter and threw it towards your father.
你點燃打火機，將此丟向父親
The lighter caused the curtains to catch fire and flare up.
火延燒至窗簾，房子熊熊燃燒
After that, you left your father there
接著你丟下浩一郎先生
and you fled the scene.
自己逃跑了
Is that correct?
我沒說錯吧？
Yes.
是的
Are you feeling all right?
你的身體還好嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
Yes.
還可以
Are you able to eat?
有正常進食嗎？
I'm eating somewhat.
勉強有
Any fever or listlessness?
有沒有發燒或疲倦的症狀？
If you feel ill in any way, please inform us.
身體不適請務必告知
Prosecutor,
檢座
you sound like a doctor.
你問這話就像醫生似的
I feel fine.
我沒問題
Please proceed.
請你繼續
All right.
好的
Actually, as a result of an inspection of the crime scene,
其實現場勘驗的結果顯示
there's a possibility the fire started outside of the house.
起火點可能在室外
Near the garage adjacent to the living room,
我們在客廳旁的車庫附近
we found evidence of a fire breaking out.
發現起火的痕跡
There were also traces of gasoline detected from there.
並從上頭驗出了汽油的成分
There is now an eyewitness account of a man roaming around the area.
同時還有目擊者供稱 看見有男子在附近徘徊
These facts don't seem to align with your statements.
這跟你先前的供詞有出入 你覺得是怎麼回事？
I wanted the fire to grow bigger.
我覺得火燒得越猛越好
After I left the house, I spread gasoline around.
所以逃到室外後潑灑了汽油
Where was the gasoline?
那汽油原本放在何處？
It was in the garage.
在車庫裡
Was it something you had prepared?
是你提前準備好的嗎？
I'd rather not say.
我要行使緘默權
Then why didn't you tell us before that you spread gasoline around?
那你在之前的問話中 為何從沒提過自己潑過汽油？
I didn't want it to be a more serious offense.
我覺得罪名加重對我不利
Right after setting the fire, you admitted to a police officer that you did it.
犯案後面對警察的詢問 你立刻坦承是自己縱的火
Even though you admitted to the crime,
你承認有犯罪
you wanted to avoid a more serious offense?
但認為罪名加重對自己不利？
Yes.
沒錯
That's right.
就是這樣
Masaki Nogi is hiding something?
野木真樹有所隱瞞？
Yes. His statement has some strange points.
對，他的供詞有許多疑點
Such as?
具體說說是哪些
First of all, he says that after an argument
首先他聲稱自己和父親吵到最後
he used a lighter he found in the room to set the fire.
拿起客廳裡的打火機點火
But his family says Mr. Koichiro Nogi quit smoking five years ago,
但根據家人的說詞 野木浩一郎先生五年前就戒菸了
and there was no lighter in the house.
住家裡並沒有打火機
Couldn't Masaki Nogi have had it with him?
那野木真樹自己持有的可能性呢？
I've considered that,
我也想過
but he's been saying he didn't have any intention of arson when he went there.
不過他供稱自己前往父親家的本意 並不是為了縱火
Koichiro is currently in the ICU.
另外，浩一郎先生目前人在加護病房
To be injured so seriously,
可見他是吸入了大量的一氧化碳
he must have inhaled a substantial amount of smoke.
才會造成如此的重症
I wondered if he failed to escape due to trying to put out the fire,
我思索過他為了滅火 來不及逃脫的可能性
but no fire extinguisher had been used.
但現場沒有使用過 滅火器那類物品的痕跡
Also, he had no pre-existing conditions. No high blood pressure or heart disease.
我還查過他是否患有高血壓 或心臟病等慢性病，但都沒有
If Masaki Nogi's statement about setting the fire in front of Koichiro is true,
假使野木真樹聲稱 自己在父親面前放火的供詞屬實
Koichiro Nogi could have escaped early on, in the same way as Masaki did.
那野木浩一郎也該像真樹那樣 在起火之初就能逃離火場
But the fact is he didn't make it out, he's unconscious, in serious condition.
但他卻沒能逃走 還身負重傷，昏迷不醒
Moreover, the crime scene inspection revealed
此外，經過現場勘驗
a piece of a burned plastic fuel can with gasoline traces.
找出了裝有汽油的塑膠桶 燃燒後留下的部分殘骸
We also have a witness who saw a suspicious man
在起火的當天晚上有目擊者回報
roaming near the house on the night of the fire.
說看見可疑男子在住家附近徘徊
When Masaki Nogi was asked about this,
我就此事向野木真樹提問
he began saying things he hadn't stated before.
他竟開始說出 先前供述時未曾提及的話
What did he say?
說了什麼？
"I wanted the fire to grow bigger."
“我覺得火燒得越猛越好
"After I left the house, I spread gasoline around."
所以逃到室外後 潑灑了放在車庫的汽油”
I see.
原來如此
Right after allegedly committing arson,
野木真樹在犯案後
Masaki was questioned by a police officer and easily admitted to his crime.
向路過的警察輕易鬆口 乾脆地承認是自己縱火
Then why didn't he mention the gasoline before?
那他最初為何不提這件事？
Is the man the eyewitness saw and Masaki Nogi the same person?
被目擊的男子和野木真樹是同一人？
Still unknown. The Yokohama Minami Police are investigating now.
目前不清楚，橫濱南署正在搜查
That means the arsonist might be still at large.
也就是說，縱火犯可能另有其人
There may be another individual besides his son who holds a grudge
除了兒子以外，還有人對野木浩一郎
against Koichiro Nogi.
懷恨在心
Yes.
沒錯
Will you allow me to investigate a little longer?
可以再讓我調查一段時間嗎？
Understood.
知道了
We'll extend the detention.
就延長拘留期限吧
Yes.
好的
Ms. Nishimura!
西村檢座…
Masaki Nogi lost consciousness in his cell, vomiting blood!
聽說野木真樹在拘留所暈倒 還吐血了！
What?
什麼？
Yes. The medical procedure is done.
對，他剛才被緊急救治
We knew he had gallbladder cancer,
我們知道他有膽囊癌
but they said it metastasized into his duodenum and made him vomit blood.
但癌細胞已經擴散到十二指腸 他吐出的血似乎就出自那處
He needs to rest for the time being, then they would consider surgery.
總之得暫時靜養 之後再考慮是否要動刀
I see.
好吧
We'll stop his detention for a while.
暫停拘留
Make the arrangements now.
你立刻去辦手續
Yes. I will. Goodbye.
好的，麻煩你了，再見
The interrogation is canceled.
訊問喊停了
Okay.
這樣啊
What is the possibility of surgery?
可以動刀的機率多高？
Possibility?
其實不該談機率
It's just that if he doesn't get surgery,
如果就這麼放著不動刀
he may not last long.
他肯定活不久
When his condition stabilizes,
我認為病情一旦回穩
he'll need it as soon as possible.
就該立即動手術
You should stay with him.
你去陪他吧
Y-You don't mind?
可以嗎？
For now…
我想他現在
it's better if someone is with him.
需要有個人陪著
Where am I?
我在哪？
The hospital.
醫院
Right.
是喔
How do you feel?
身體感覺怎麼樣？
Oh, the worst.
很糟，糟透了
The prosecutor's interrogation is a pain.
檢座的訊問太難熬了
About my illness…
你早就知道…
Did you know?
我的病情了？
I heard from your doctor.
是主治醫師告訴我的
I see.
原來如此
Hey.
我問你
Did you really set the fire?
你真的縱火了嗎？
You're still asking?
到現在還要問？
I might vomit blood again.
我可能又要吐血了
Okay.
好吧
I won't ask for now.
我不問了
It was so hard.
我好痛苦
Kanade.
你坐在我對面
We were face-to-face for hours.
好幾個小時
You were right there…
你明明…
so close to me.
就在我身邊
But you're the prosecutor.
卻是檢察官的身分
Staring at me with a scary face.
臉上的表情可怕極了
And I even had a rope… around my waist.
我的腰上還被綁上繩子
That can't be helped.
那也沒辦法啊
Hey.
小奏
Hold out your hand.
你伸出手
What are you saying?
你在說什麼啦？
Here.
伸手
It's Kanade's hand.
是小奏的手
So soft.
好軟
Kanade.
小奏
Hmm?
嗯？
You asked me…
你已經聽說…
why I came back to Japan.
我回日本的原因了吧？
Yeah.
對
You want to know…
要我告訴你…
the real reason?
真正的原因嗎？
Huh? What is it? Tell me.
什麼？究竟為何？告訴我
Kanade.
小奏
I wanted to see you.
因為我想見你一面
Of course,
不過呢
my father…
當然也是因為老爸…
and Kaori
還有香織
were part of it too.
這也不能否認
But…
只不過啊
you were more important.
那些其實都不重要
When I thought…
就在我認為
I might die soon,
自己可能會死的時候
the one I wanted to be with
我最後想陪的人
is you, Kanade.
就只有你
So that's why…
所以說啊…
I came back to see you.
我是專程回來找你
But then…
然而…
this whole thing happened.
事情卻演變至此
I'm such an idiot.
我好蠢啊
Why do things
我怎麼每次都這樣？
always turn out the wrong way for me?
總是讓事態朝不正常的方向發展呢？
I guess it's my own fault, huh?
難道真的是我不好？
It is all your fault.
確實是你不好
The things you do are always messed up.
你做事往往都是魯莽亂來
You're selfish.
任性妄為
You do as you please.
凡事只顧著自己
And you're self-righteous.
不聽別人的勸告
You've always been that way.
從很久之前就是這樣
And you just go away without telling anybody.
還不做任何解釋就突然離開
It's the same even now.
就連現在也是
Kanade.
小奏
Want to run away?
要不要私奔？
Let's run away.
我們一起逃吧
Just the two of us.
就我們兩個
I want to be with you.
我想和你待在一起
I want to see that starry sky…
我想再次和你…
with you alone.
去看那片星空
That was the second crime…
那是我犯下的…
I ever committed.
第二個罪過
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Sachs
字幕翻譯：劉維容
I don't mind dying if I'm with you, Kanade.
能跟小奏在一起，我死而無憾
Masaki Nogi is missing?
聽說野木真樹不見了？
I have a question.
我有事想問你
You're hiding something.
你對我有所隱瞞吧？
Masaki.
真樹
What's the truth?
所謂的真相究竟是什麼？
-It was recorded on the dashcam. -What?
-行車記錄器拍到了 -這是怎麼回事？
What were you doing in front of the house that day?
那天你在房子前的路上做什麼？